Register of the Carol Green Wilson Papers, ca. 1949-1975
Hoover Institution Archives
Carol Green Wilson Papers,
ca. 1949-1975
70003
Wilson, Carol Green, 1892-
13 manuscript boxes 5.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, clippings, and other printed matter, relating primarily to the life of Herbert Hoover. Includes material used as research for the book by C. G. Wilson, entitled Herbert Hoover: A Challenge for Today.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1970.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Fiedler, Arthur, 1894-; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; United States--Politics and government.
Biographical Note
1892, April 16 Born, Livingston, Montana
1914 A.B., Stanford University
1914 Married George Osborn Wilson
1918-1921 Editor, Stanford Alumni magazine
1928-1935 Editor, Stanford Alumni magazine
1931 Author, Chinatown Quest
1946 Author, California Yankee
1949 Author, Gump's Treasure Trade
1956 Author, Alice Eastwood's Wonderland
1956 Author, We Who Wear Kites
1968 Author, Arthur Fielder: Music for the Millions
1968 Author, Herbert Hoover: A Challenge for Today
1981 Died, Connecticut
Series Description
- WRITINGS, 1949-1968. (Box Boxes 1-6.)
  Relevant correspondence, notes, drafts, and reviews of books written by Carol Green Wilson, arranged alphabetically by title.
- CORRESPONDENCE FILE, ca. 1949-1975. (Box Boxes 7-8.)
  Correspondence of Carol Green Wilson, arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
- SUBJECT FILE, ca. 1949-1975. (Box Boxes 9-13.)
  Clippings, printed matter, articles and correspondence by others collected by Carol Green Wilson, arranged alphabetically by subject.
Container List
- WRITINGS
  - Alice Eastwood's Wonderland (Box 1.)
    - Typescript, n.d., Carbon copy
    - Review by Alice Mary Greer, April, 1966., Photocopy
  - Arthur Fielder: Music for the Millions
    - Correspondence
      - General
      - Fielder, Arthur, 1949-1967
    - Notes, n.d., Typescript and holographs. (3 folders)
    - Typescript, n.d., (3 folders)
    - Typescript, n.d. (Box 2.)
    - Reviews and notices, ca. 1968
    - Miscellaneous
  - Chinatown Quest
    - Advertisement and order form, n.d.
  - Gump's Treasure Trade
    - Correspondence, ca. 1949-1966
    - Notes, ca. 1947-1960., Typescript and holographs
    - Typescript, n.d., Original and carbon copies
    - Reviewsand notices, ca. 1949-1967
  - Herbert Hoover: A Challenge for Today (Box 3.)
    - Printed copy, 1968
    - Correspondence
      - General
      - Adams, Florence (Mrs. Sidney)
      - Albright, Horace Marden
      - Allan, Evelyn Wight (Mrs. Mansfield)
      - Allen, Peter C.
      - American Friends Service Committee
      - Ashley, Roscoe L.
      - Barker, Burt Brown
      - Blythe, Charles R.
      - Bradley, Worthen
      - Brown, Walter L.
      - Castle, W. R.
      - Clark, Birge M.
      - Columbia University
      - Downe, George
      - Drury, Newton B.
      - Friends Meeting of Washington
      - Fullerton, Hugh
      - Galpin, Perrin C.
      - Gardner, Edith (Mrs. Nathaniel L.)
      - General Petroleum Corporation
      - Gregg, C. L.
      - Grew, Joseph C.
      - Grosjean, Paul
      - Hague, Marian
      - Herter, Christian
      - Hinshaw, David
      - Hoover, Allan
      - Hoover, Herbert
      - Hoover, Margaret
      - Hoover, Margaret
      - Hoover, Theodore
      - Hotchkiss, Mr.
      - James, Harlean
      - Janin, Mrs. Charles
      - Jones, Elizabeth B.
      - Jorgenson, Henry I.
      - Kellogg, Charlotte
      - Kellogg, Jean
      - Kendrick, Mr.
      - Kent, Fred I.
      - Lassner, Franz G.
      - Leavitt, Mary Hoover
      - Lee, Jim
      - Lewis, Dorothy
      - McAtee, Sylvester J.
      - McCormick, Robert L.
      - McNab, John L.
      - Miller, Adolph
      - Miller, Bernice
      - Mitchell, Derne
      - Mullendore, William C.
      - Nash, Bradley D.
      - Pate, Maurice
      - Pennington, Levi T. (Box 4.)
      - Perry, Henry H.
      - Phillips, Edna
      - Redfern, Gilbert
      - Rice, Archie
      - Richardson, Mrs.
      - Rickard, Mr.
      - Searls, Robert M.
      - Seling, Flora
      - Small, Laurine A. (Mrs. Horatio L.)
      - Stephen, Alice King
      - Sterling, Morton
      - Stillman, E. Clark
      - Sullivan, Lawrence
      - Tamplin, William J.
      - Torrey, Clark M.
      - Trueblood, Elton
      - Tuck, Hallam
      - UNICEF
      - Vaux, Mary Jane (Mrs. Walter)
      - Vickery, Mrs. Frederick
      - Wickett, Frederick A.
      - Zion, Edwin R.
    - Notes. All notes are undated and holographs, unless otherwise indicated.
      - General., Holograph and typescript. (2 folders)
      - Addresses Upon the American Road., Typescript
      - Allen, Frederick L., Since Yesterday., Typescript
      - American Relief Administration, 1919-1920.
      - Beard, Charles and Mary, America in Midpassage., Typescript
      - Campaign, 1920.
      - Campaign, 1932., Typescript
      - Carnegie Food Research Institute., Typescript
      - Commission for Relief in Belgium., Holograph and typescript
      - Crisis, 1929.
      - Election, 1928.
      - Food Administration, 1917-1918., Holograph and typescript
      - Grain to India.
      - Herbert Hoover and Stanford., Typescript
      - Hoover, Herbert, An American Epic., Typescript and holograph
      - Hoover Commission on the Reorganization of the Executive Branch of the Government., Typescript
      - Jean Kellogg's Description of Herbert Hoover's Funeral in West Branch, Iowa., Typescript (Box 5.)
      - Kittredge (Henry) Notes., Typescript
      - Lochner, Louis, Herbert Hoover and Germany., Typescript
      - London and Belgian Relief.
      - Lou Henry Hoover.
      - McCormick, Robert E., interview with.
      - McKensie, E. L., interview with.
      - Memoirs of Cordell Hull., Typescript
      - Meyer, Eugene, interview with.
      - Miller, Adolph, interview with., Typescript
      - Mining, 1895-1914.
      - Norris papers.
      - Page, Walter H., The Life and Letters of Walter H. Page., Typescript
      - Page letters., Typescript
      - Peace Conference, 1916-1919.
      - Personal interviews.
      - President, 1929-1933., Typescript
      - Rickard, Mr., interview with.
      - Robinson, Henry Morton, Fantastic Interim., Typescript
      - Secretary of Commerce, 1920-1928., Typescript and holograph
      - Seventy-fifth Birthday.
      - Small, Mrs. Horatio, interview with., Typescript
      - South American Trip., Typescript
      - Speeches on World Affairs, 1932-1950., Typescript
      - Stanford, 1891-1895., Typescript and holograph
      - Stanford Illustrated Review., Typescript
      - Stanford - Food Research Institute, Business School, Hoover Library.
      - Stanford Home Trustee Union.
      - Stanford University Commencement Address, 1935., Typescript
      - Trip to Europe, 1938.
      - Tuck, Hallam, interview with.
      - Warren, Harris G., Herbert Hoover and the Great Depression., Typescript and holograph
      - William Allen White Correspondence, 1933-1936 Regarding New Deal.
      - World Food Conditions.
      - Youth and Family.
    - Typescript
      - Fragments, n.d., Originals and carbon copies
      - Preface and Acknowledgements, n.d., Originals and carbon copies
      - Preface, Chapters 1-10, n.d., Originals and carbon copies (Box 6.)
      - Chapters 11-29, n.d., Originals and carbon copies
      - Chapters 30-34, n.d., Originals and carbon copies
    - Galley proof, n.d.
    - Reviews and notices
  - A History of the Heritage, 1853-1970, 1970., Printed copy
  - How Bert Hoover Met Lou Henry, 1965., Braille copy (Box 7.)
- CORRESPONDENCE
  - Unidentified (Box 7.)
  - Abel, Hazel
  - American Institute of Mining, Metallurgical and Petroleum Engineers
  - Anderson, Raezella
  - Aswell, Mr.
  - Atheneum Publishers
  - Atlantic Monthly Press
  - Authors Guild
  - Bean, Mr.
  - Belgian-American Educational Foundation
  - Bennett, T. W.
  - Boston Symphony Orchestra
  - Braille Mirror
  - Burchtaill, Larry
  - Charles E. Tuttle Co., Inc.
  - Children's Health Council of the Mid-Peninsula
  - Choate, Stuart
  - Coward McCann, Inc.
  - Crawford, Hilary H.
  - Crowell-Collier Publishing Co.
  - Crown Publishers, Inc.
  - David McKay Co., Inc.
  - Dickie, Jean K.
  - Doubleday and Co.
  - Elliot, Marian P. (Mrs. L. Patterson)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica Press (Box 8.)
  - Evans, Betsy H.
  - Fish, Bobby
  - Fles, Barthold
  - G. P. Putnam's Sons
  - Harper and Row
  - Hawthorn Books
  - Henry Regnery Co.
  - Hinderer, Marion (Mrs. Kenneth)
  - Hinds, Mr.
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc.
  - Hoover Institution
  - Houghton Mifflin Co.
  - Humphrey, Lany
  - Huntington Library
  - Iowa State University Press
  - Kemp, Dr.
  - Kosciuzko Foundation
  - Lane Magazine Co.
  - J. B. Lippincott Co.
  - Little, Brown and Co.
  - Mc Cormack, William E.
  - McGraw Hill Book Co.
  - McInnis, Grace (Mrs. Emmett)
  - McIntosh and Otis, Inc.
  - Macmillan Co.
  - Martin, Leonard B.
  - Mattei, Bert
  - Mayo, Waldo
  - Mifflin, John
  - Millikan, Robert A.
  - Oxford University Press
  - Page, Virginia (Mrs. Benjamin)
  - Phillips, Leila Douglas
  - R. R. Bowker Co.
  - Random House, Inc.
  - Red Lion Inn
  - Reiss, Malcolm
  - Ridge Press
  - San Fransisco Chronicle
  - San Fransisco Literary Agency, Inc.
  - Seydell, Mildred
  - Slenczynska, Ruth
  - Smith, Ethyl Sabin (Mrs. Willard M.)
  - Stanford Review
  - Stanford University Press
  - Stein and Day Publishers
  - Storke, Thomas M.
  - Summerfield, Lester D.
  - Sutton, Mr.
  - Tatum, Frank D.
  - Thomas Y. Crowell Co.
  - University of California Press
  - University Chicago Press
  - Viking Press
  - W. W. Norton and Co., Inc.
  - Wing, Willis Kingsley
  - Wilson, G. Osborne
  - Wilson, Lloyd
  - Wilson, Neill C.
- SUBJECT FILE
  - Belgian-American Educational Foundation (Box 9.)
  - La Belgique et l'Entree en Guerre des Etats-Unis (Belgium and the Entry of the United States in the War)
  - Biographical file - general
  - Bliven, Bruce
  - Davis, J. S., The Food Research Institute, 1921-1941: An Interpretation., Excerpt, photocopy
  - European trip, ca. 1950. Itinerary
  - Fiedler, Arthur
    - General
    - Clippings
    - Legal dispute., Letters and notes, originals and photocopies
  - Foote, Arthur B., Men and Mines., Typescript, photocopy
  - Hoover, Herbert
    - General
    - Clippings
    - Clippings (Box 10.)
    - Memorabilia
    - Original letter to Colonel P. M. (Happy) Hazzard, September 7, 1954
    - Speeches and Writings
      - Miscellaneous
      - A-B
      - C-E
      - F-H
      - I-L
      - M-Q
      - R-S (Box 11.)
      - T-V
      - W-Z
  - Hoover Foundation for the University of Louvain
  - Horta, Victor
  - McDonnell, R. E.
  - Paderewski, Ignace
  - Pate, Maurice
  - Pflieger, Colonel Robert P.
  - Publishers
  - Stanford Illustrated Review (marked by Carol Green Wilson for articles on Herbert Hoover)
    - Vol. 20
    - Vol. 21
    - Vol. 22
    - Vol. 29 (Box 12.)
    - Vol. 30
    - Vol. 31
    - Vol. 32
    - Vol. 33 (Box 13.)
    - Vol. 34
    - Vol. 35
    - Vol. 36
  - Stanford Review, May-June, 1965
  - UNICEF